Let's move ahead in the corporate connection and
today we are joined by the
management of ICICI Lombard. The company is one of the
leading private general insurance companies in the country
whose portfolio includes
many insurance products like motor health, crop, personal accident.
Today we will discuss
their growth outlook with the management of the company and will also
discuss the third quarter results in detail. Gopal Balachandra,
CFO of ICICI Lombard has joined us.
Mr. Balachandra,
thank you very much for your time. You are welcome to our
state. First of all, we will talk about your numbers
and strong performance. A
good trend of strength has been seen on a quarterly basis, particularly because of the
combined ratio which has gone below the level of 102,
largely driven by loss ratio. So, the
scenario of the combined ratio is, will it be
seen to decrease further from here? 101 which is
your guided range,
we
will see it reaching there. It is a very good question. If you have
seen that the strategy of ICICI is that
we have generally focused a lot on profitable growth
and this is not a recent thing, but
if you how many  If we go back a year, in
general, our thought process in terms
of driving growth is that we have
stuck to profitable growth. That is why, if
you look at the last two-three years, when there was a
lot of market advancement,
we actually let go of market share.
And as of today, I think some of that
market share is coming back for us. And therefore, our
approach will be that even going
forward, we will continue to kind of stay
focused on profitable growth. But regarding your
question, in the context of the combined ratio, if
you look at the combined ratio of quarter three of last year,
on a reported basis, it was slightly
above 103. And
if you look at quarter three of this year,
our reported combined ratio was
102.7. If you remember, there were some
catastrophic events in quarter three of last year due to which the
combined ratio was slightly
elevated. If you
remove the impact of catastrophic events, then the
combined ratio of quarter three of last year would
become  It goes to 102.3 and the
number for the fourth quarter of this year is 102.7, but there
is a small deviation in that too, where
effective first of October, our
insurance regulator, VIE IRDAI, has
brought a change where the
recognition of long term products will be
over the period of the contract and
whatever your cost of
acquisition is on top of that, that too will be recognized over the
period of time. So if you remove that impact
also and look at the numbers on
BU basis, business as usual basis, then
our reported combined was 102.7
and that will be
102.3. So in that sense, if you see,
in both the quarters, the relative combined rate is
largely maintained. But your question was in
terms of text, I think in general, if you
look over the last two three years, our
rate has been seeing a decline and as
I said, our approach is in terms
of driving profitability.
We will focus on growth going forward as well and
since one should expect to see a reduction in
the combined ratios going forward as well, the
kind of targets you are setting for absolute combined ratio, we
hope that
you are able to meet such targets as well, but
growth was also seen from the motor segment, particularly
during the quarter for your business and
this was largely added by the festive
season, support was seen from there to a great extent,
but on the other hand,
if we talk about wholesale vehicle sales, weak numbers were
seen there, will the growth be sustained in the future
and what will be your plan for wholesale vehicle sales, I
think it is a very good question, again I
think if you see that for us motor is a very very important
preferred segment, but if you
look at the numbers of quarter three or nine
months,
in comparison to the industry, the growth numbers of IC Labad,
I think we have had
reasonably relative out performance and we
think  That going forward also I think one should continue to see out
performance vis-à-vis the
market. So as I said earlier,
our market share which we had lost
in the last two-three years because of our approach to
drive profitable growth, as of today I
think we have been able to
recoup some of the lost market share. If you
look at today's market
share of Ilabad and motor has been slightly more than
11, so hence to that extent I think
our positioning has been that it has been very very
positive. Your question was in
terms of how the growth will play out. If
you talk about motor insurance, I think
our growth it comes across two
aspects, one is whatever
our growth will be on new vehicle insurance
and second is our assisting
slash renewal book, there is a
lot of positive growth potential for us in that too.
So if you look at
our again if relatively, if we look
consistently at new vehicle
If the growth momentum slows down, then obviously
we will take a cautious stand. Absolutely,
Mr. Bal Chandran. Now let's talk about the health
insurance segment and the
loss ratio of the health insurance segment. If we
talk about it, these have been seen in a relatively comfortable range
for the company, but we have
also heard weak commentary
across the industry in the recent past. So, keeping this in mind, what would
you say? Do you think the loss ratios can
remain inflated for the segment in the coming days as well. And are
you anticipating any price hike for the loans?
Again, one of our
preferred segments, but if you look at
health loans, it is divided into two parts,
one is retail health insurance and the
other is commercial and group health
insurance.
Again, if you look at
total health on a nine-month basis, if you look at it, then again
ICC Lombard has had a relative outperformance compared
to the industry growth
numbers. And with that, if you look at retail
health, we have been there for the last three years.  We have been
making significant
investments in driving
distribution and coming out with new
products. Our growth on that has been quite good. In
fact, this quarter, while the
industry growth has been in single digits,
ICS lumped growth on retail
health has been almost around 19%.
So, we have had a very good performance in
retail health and thanks to the new
product we launched this quarter,
which we have talked about earlier, called
Elevate, that has been well received by
various stakeholders. So, here our
momentum in the retail health growth segment, I
think that is again looking very, very
promising. So, then to the
extent, generally, the rates have come back.
Okay, Mr. Bal Chandran,
if we talk about this quarter, RE has gone above 20% levels.
It is higher than the guided range.
So, will it be possible to imagine that RE will
remain in the upper band as per
your guidance, which  The outcome of RO on 16 to 18 is a
combination of many
factors. It is a function
of your growth, it is a function of
your profitability and it is a function of
various income streams. What we
said in 16 to 18, if
you see that whenever we make a lot of
investments in terms of future
areas, the accounting
requirement as of today is to kind of expense
out less investment for future
opportunity in the current period, but
if we see equally, wherever we
see an opportunity for profitability, it is
contributed by outcomes,
but in general, the range that we talked about,
ideally you have to look at the range
over multiple financial periods and
in the longer term, the range of 16 to 18 per cent range will be a
comfortable operating to set
if the trajectory of combined share that
I talked about, clearly it is  Seeing a
decline in the way we have been able to see the
overall combined ratio playout
Absolutely Mr. Bal Chandran, thank you very much for
joining us, answering the questions
and best
wishes to you for the coming quarters. So this is the
management of ICICI Lombard talking in detail about the company's
results, fundamental plans, business
outlook and what is the strategy for further growth and expansion.
On this note,
our fundamental expert Vive is with us. You must be
listening to the management's conversation.
We talked to the management of ICICI Lombard.
They
explained their development plans in detail and the results also looked decent on the
face of it. What would be your opinion about
this entire segment?
If you look at the entire segment in terms of overall terms, it is a
very good segment. This
particular general insurance space
here, even today if you look at under insurance,
it is
very good. In fact, I was reading a data from the
Ministry of Highways where they are
saying that almost 70% of vehicles are
properly insured even today or else  If it
runs without insurance, then this is just one of the
examples. So I think that as
awareness increases in this sector, overall this
sector will do very well in the future. It is
not necessary that
you will see a lot of performance in the short term. Of course, there has been a
correction in the valuations, that is
a comfortable level, but if there is a little correction from here, then the
general
insurance space will really do very well
and in particular, it will be one of my
favorite picks.
If you look at the PSU companies, then
I like the private companies in the general space
better because their system, which
we also deal with, is known for it, and
all that is stronger
and more effective compared to
PSU. So, private sector general
insurance is for the long term. Yes,
Vivek, thank you for joining us,
answering questions, and sharing
your fundamental outlook on the market and sector specific
with us.